Peter Verzhanskyi . Jarvis Consulting

I am a recent graduate from George Brown College seeking a Software Developer or Data Engineer role. With three years of college experience and nearly a decade in the IT industry, I have worked on multiple projects that fueled my passion for building user-friendly, accessible, and inclusive applications that improve efficiency and productivity. My proficiency in Java, JavaScript, Python, Laravel, and other technologies complements my strong communication and collaboration skills, developed both during my college tenure and through years of professional experience in the IT/Tech industry. By prioritizing feedback and using an iterative development process, I ensure that my empathy for the client experience allows me to exceed expectations. I thrive in fast-paced environments where my skills, resilience, and adaptability shine, and I am eager to bring my enthusiasm and expertise to your team by delivering exceptional software solutions.

Skills

Proficient: Java, JavaScript, Python, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, NoSQL/MongoDB, Agile/Scrum, Git

Competent: NextJS, Laravel, Angular, iOS Development, ReactNative, HTML/CSS

Familiar: C#/.NET, Android Development, TypeScript, SpringBoot, jQuery

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_PeterVerzhanskyi

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Created and deployed a Linux cluster monitoring agent built on a Docker-contained PostgreSQL database to perform data analysis about node performance. Developed a bash script to automate creating/starting/stopping the PSQL Docker container based on arguments to the script. Automated the creation of PSQL database tables using a custom DDL script. Developed shell scripts to connect to the PSQL database and populate tables using Linux hardware monitoring commands. Automated the collection of node usage data on a one-minute interval using crontab. Built and manually tested the app in a Google Cloud Platform (GCP) provisioned virtual machine using Rocky Linux 9 as the operating system.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Grep App: Developed a robust simulation of the Linux Grep Command Line Tool in Core Java. Leveraged Maven for build management and Docker for deployment. This tool allows users to input a regex pattern, specify a starting directory, and select an output file, generating a comprehensive list of matched lines for further analysis, enhancing search efficiency and data handling.
- Stock Quote App: Developed a Personal Stock Wallet application in Core Java, allowing users to buy, sell, and track stocks effortlessly. Integrated an external RESTful API for real-time stock data retrieval and utilized PostgreSQL via JDBC for managing a centralized repository of stock information. This platform-independent application ensures seamless operation across various systems, enhancing user experience and accessibility.

Springboot App [GitHub]: Not Started

Python Data Analytics [GitHub]: Not Started

Hadoop [GitHub]: Not Started
Spark [GitHub]: Not Started

Cloud/DevOps [GitHub]: Not Started

Highlighted Projects

Capstone Project: MaplePay app [GitHub]: MaplePay is a Capstone Project, built using NoSQL/MongoDB, Angular and React. It is a fintech demo project, built to provide a seamless experience through a Web-app and a ReactNative solution.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2024-present): Collaborated with an agile team to support the development of multiple projects. Created a Linux cluster monitoring agent to collect node performance data, leveraging Docker, Bash scripting, and PostgreSQL.

Junior Full-Stack Developer, 789ten.com (2024-2024): Contributed to fixing various bugs and completeing different tasks in NextJS and Laravel applications. Created clear, well-documented pull requests and worked closely with lead developers to prioritize tasks in a ticketing system. Utilized SQL expertise to optimize slow-performing queries.

System Administrator/IT Consultant, Ponacka Capital Ltd. (2017-2023): Oversaw a Windows-based environment, ensuring optimal system performance and security. Managed hardware maintenance, performed system upgrades, and implemented improvements. Delivered technical support to staff, resolving issues efficiently and boosting productivity.

Education

George Brown College (2021-2024), Advanced College Diploma, Computer Programming and Analysis - Multiple Scholarships - IEEEXtreme 17: #3 in Canada, #573 Worldwide

V. N. Karazin Kharkiv National University (2009-2014), Master of Applied Physics, Radio Physics and Radio Electronics, Speciality: Quantum Physics - Scholarships

Miscellaneous

- Placeholder
- Placeholder
- Canadian metal musician. Multiple artist grant receipient.